<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Github on CobraStatistics</title>
    <link>/tags/github/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Github on CobraStatistics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a blog with Rstudio and Hugo</title>
      <link>/2017/02/create-a-blog-with-rstudio-and-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 13:19:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/create-a-blog-with-rstudio-and-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- BLOGDOWN-HEAD --&gt;
&lt;!-- /BLOGDOWN-HEAD --&gt;

&lt;!-- BLOGDOWN-BODY-BEFORE --&gt;
&lt;!-- /BLOGDOWN-BODY-BEFORE --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a step by step tutorial on how to make your own blog with Rstudio and Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;step-one-create-github-account&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step one: Create github account&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sign up on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://github.com/&lt;/a&gt;. Github will be used as a host for your website and your profilename on github will be in the url-adress for your site, so choose your github-name wisely because you will not be able to change it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;step-two-install-blogdown-and-hugo&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step two: Install blogdown and Hugo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a new folder, mine is called ‘rweb’ but you can name it whatever you want, on your computer wich will be your working direktory. Open Rstudio and click on new projekt and then choose existing directory wich will be the new folder you just created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next is installing blogdown and Hugo and setting your working directory. Dont forget to change to your own path in ‘setwd()’ if you copy the code below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;install.packages(&amp;quot;blogdown&amp;quot;)
install_hugo(version = &amp;quot;latest&amp;quot;, use_brew = T, force)
setwd(&amp;quot;C:/Users/Konrad/rweb&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Troubles? if not continue to next step, else run ‘install.packages(“evaluate”)’, it might clear up some errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;step-three-create-two-repositories&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step three: Create two repositories&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;open &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://github.com/&lt;/a&gt; and log on to your profile. Click on ‘+’ in the upper-right corner and choose New repository which &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; have the same name as your github account. Click the little box wich says “Initialize this repository with a README” above the green ‘Create repository’ button. Click on the green button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do the same procedure once again to make the second repository. This one you can call whatever you want. I called mine ‘blog’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;step-four-clone-your-repository&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step four: Clone your repository&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you dont allready have git bash istalled you can download it from &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-for-windows.github.io/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://git-for-windows.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to your second github repository and click on *Clone or download’ and copy the URL-adress. Open git bash and type the following code which creates a clone of the repository on your computer. Unix commands is used in git bash and here is a useful cheatcheet &lt;a href=&#34;http://mally.stanford.edu/~sr/computing/basic-unix.html/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://mally.stanford.edu/~sr/computing/basic-unix.html/&lt;/a&gt;, look specifically under ‘Directories’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Use pwd to see were you are standing right now.
pwd

# Use cd to navigate to your working directory. Mine is called &amp;#39;rweb&amp;#39;.
cd rweb # you can go through several folders att once, ex: cd Users/yourname/newfolder

# when you are standing in your working directory type &amp;#39;git clone&amp;#39; and paste the url from your second repository.
git clone &amp;#39;repository-url&amp;#39;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now there should be a new folder, named after your second repository, in your projectfolder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;step-five-create-website-locally&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step five: Create website locally&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open your R-project file and change working directory to your new cloned folder inside your current working directory. The next step requires your working directory (e.g. cloned folder) to be empty, therefore move the README-file temporarely out of your cloned folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(blogdown)
setwd(&amp;quot;path-to-your-cloned-fodler&amp;quot;)
new_site() # only run this once&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you should see your new website in the viewer window and also a hello-world.rmd file poped up. Now stop the session before proceeding to the newxt step. The is a stopsign in the top-right corner of your console-window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;step-six-deploy-your-website&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step six: Deploy your website&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open git bash and type the following code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Navigate to your cloned folder with cd if you not allready in it.
cd clonedfolder

# Remove the public with following code (public will ge regenerated again, no worries)
rm -rf public

# Kind of cloning your first repository to  a new public folder. Change &amp;#39;username&amp;#39; to your own username before running the code.
git submodule add -b master git@github.com:username/username.github.io.git public&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run the serve_site() function in Rstudio to regenerate all files that whree deleted in previous step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;serve_site()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;step-seven-deploy-your-website-on-github&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step seven: Deploy your website on github&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# navigate to the public folder
cd public

# adding changes to git
git add -A

# comment what changes have been done
git commit -m &amp;quot;your-message-whithin-the-citationmarks&amp;quot;

# Pushing your lokal website live on internet
git push origin master&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whithin a couple of minutes your website is hosted at &lt;a href=&#34;https://yourusername.github.io/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://yourusername.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;. Yay!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>